progressive.com 2001-06-04

# Progressive Privacy Policy

|  |  |   |  | **Privacy Policy** | Last updated May 15, 2001  
---|---  
  
**Your privacy is important to us**. At Progressive, we are committed to protecting your privacy and earning your trust. We respect your right to keep your personal information confidential and to avoid unwanted solicitations. **Please read this to learn how we will handle your personal information.**

**Types of Information We Collect and Disclose**

We collect information about people and property to quote and service insurance policies and provide comparison rates. Some of this is called **"Nonpublic Personal Information,"** which generally means information that is provided by you, obtained by us, or that results from your transactions with us. It does not include information available to the general public. We collect this information from the following sources (examples under each source are not necessarily a complete list):

  * **Application Information:** This is information we receive from you on applications or other forms, by phone, and online. It includes your name, address, and telephone number, driver’s license number, social security number, date of birth, length of employment, gender, marital status, prior insurance information, home ownership status, length of residency, vehicle descriptions, miles driven and vehicle use, other drivers, and driving history. **Application Information** may be disclosed as described below.
  * **Transaction Information:** This is information about your transactions with us, our affiliates, or others. It includes your insurance coverage selections and premiums, payment and claims history, and information necessary for billing and payment. It may also include additional information obtained while adjusting, investigating, and settling insurance claims. **Transaction Information** may be disclosed as described below. 
  * **Consumer Report Information:** This is information we receive from a consumer reporting agency. It is used to confirm or supplement **Application Information** so that we may underwrite your insurance and provide an accurate premium quote for one of our insurance underwriting companies. It includes motor vehicle reports, claims history reports, and credit report information. We will disclose **Consumer Report Information** only as we deem necessary to quote or service your insurance policy, and as permitted or required by law. 
  * **Web Site Information:** This is information we receive from your computer when you visit our Web site that is unique to e-commerce transactions. It includes the Web site you visited before ours, your Internet e-mail address and operating system, and statistical information on Web traffic and usage patterns. We also store "cookies" on your computer to save information entered during the insurance quoting and comparative rate process, and collect technical data, such as your Internet protocol (IP) address, operating system, and session ID. We will not disclose your e-mail address to nonaffiliated third parties for their marketing purposes. We might use external vendors for processing our e-mail messages, but they will not be allowed to keep your e-mail address for their future use. We will not disclose other personally identifiable **Web Site Information** without your consent. Additional information concerning our Web site privacy practices appears below.

**Parties to Whom We Disclose Information**

**Nonpublic Personal Information** about you may be disclosed to others as permitted by law. Generally, this includes disclosures to third parties that we feel are necessary to effect, administer or enforce your transaction with us, or in connection with servicing your insurance policy. These parties may include our group of affiliated insurance underwriting companies, claims representatives, independent contractors, insurance support organizations, insurance agents and brokers, and courts and government agencies. We may also disclose this information to the following types of third parties (these are typically companies that have referred you to us or that have a relationship with you), but you will have the opportunity to opt out of such disclosures before they are made: 

  * Nonaffiliated financial service providers, such as banks, credit card companies, and other insurance companies; and 
  * Non-financial companies, such as motor vehicle manufacturers, dealers, and parts suppliers, and clubs and associations of which you may be a member. 

We may also disclose **Application Information** and **Transaction Information** about you to companies that perform marketing services on our behalf or to financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements.  

**Confidentiality & Security**

We restrict access to **Nonpublic Personal Information** about you to those employees and other parties who we feel must use that information to provide products or services to you. Their right to further disclose and use the information is limited by our employee code of conduct, applicable law, and nondisclosure agreements where appropriate. We also maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards in compliance with applicable laws and regulations to guard your **Nonpublic Personal Information**. 

**Parties to Whom This Privacy Policy Applies**

This Privacy Policy applies to current and former customers of Progressive Casualty Insurance Company and its family of insurance and financial services companies in the United States. For a list of the companies to which this Privacy Policy applies, click here.

This replaces all previous privacy policies that we have made available to you as of the date noted above for products and services available through progressive.com. For different products, you may receive other privacy policies from us. These other policies will apply only to the products in connection with which they are provided.  
**  
Additional Information for Web Site Visitors**

Progressive uses comprehensive measures on our Web site to protect your privacy and secure your personal information. When we collect information from visitors to progressive.com, we use it to provide service to you and better understand what our customers want so that we can continue to enhance your online experience. Visitors to Progressive's Web site browse anonymously, and are not required to provide any personal information in order to access our Web site. We do receive from your computer **Web Site Information** to help us evaluate what our consumers want, provide adequate capacity for our visitors, and display information in the best manner.   
**  
Web Site Information** helps us understand who you are and what information you looked for when you visited our site, so that the next time you visit progressive.com, your experience will be even better. For example, if you visit our site and obtain an insurance quote, but decide to come back later to continue processing that quote, we are able to save your information so you can pick up where you left off. Information that does not identify you, and information collected when you participate in contests and surveys, may be used for marketing purposes. 

When you quote or buy insurance on progressive.com, we collect your e-mail address so that we can send you an e-mail confirming your rate and policy information. At your request, we will also use this address to provide you reminders about our products and services. Even if you request them, you can opt out of receiving future e-mail reminders from Progressive at any time by sending an e-mail to [webmaster@progressive.com](mailto:webmaster@progressive.com). 

**Third Party Cookies**

When you visit Web sites with advertising, those sites often use a third party ad serving company to "serve" (deliver) the banner ad graphics that are part of the page you see:

A visit to progressive.com is similar, but instead of a large banner ad, the ad company may serve a small graphic (1x1 pixel):

When the ad serving company sends their graphics, they send a cookie to your browser's cookie file. The purpose of the third party cookie is to allow advertisers, like progressive.com, to receive aggregated, non-personally identifiable information in reports from the third party company. This information is used to audit the third party ad company, confirm the placement of our ads, and improve our ability to select the best sites on which to advertise.

By design, cookies can only be accessed by the company that places them, so no cookie information is shared between the ad server, the content site, or progressive.com. For more information about third party cookies and setting your preferences, visit [PrivacyChoices.org](http://www.privacychoices.org/).  

**Web Site Security**

Our systems are configured to provide privacy, integrity, and authentication in Internet communications. The security measures we have taken help ensure that your data is secure and encrypted, so that a third party cannot capture, read or access the information while it is in transit between your computer and our system. 

Specifically, we use a secure server and security protocol to safeguard the information you provide during the purchase and payment processes. We use a secure server implementing the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol to interact with you when you provide personal information during the purchase and payment processes. We handle your information via 128 bit encryption. Every secure page on progressive.com has been secured with a digital certificate by RSA Data Security/Secure Server CA. This is shown via the site certificate that resides on all secure pages. To view this certificate, click on the image of the "closed lock" or the "solid key" on the bottom of your browser window. A small frame displaying site security information will appear. Click on "subject" to verify that you are on a progressive.com site. Click on "Issuer" to verify the site certification authority. 

We limit internal access to our servers and require that Progressive people adhere to high standards of ethics and integrity in performing their jobs and conducting business. 

**Web Site Links**

Our Web site contains links to third party sites that are not maintained by us. These links are provided solely for your convenience. We make no warranties or representations about the contents of or any products or services offered by third-party sites. We recommend that you read the privacy and security policies of these sites. 

**Glossary**

**Cookie:** A small text file of information saved in the browser when you access certain Web pages. Cookies hold information that identifies you to the Web site (and only that Web site) that gave you the cookie.

**Digital certificate:** A small file that can be transferred to your computer over the Internet and used for authentication. Once installed, a digital certificate can be automatically detected and used as needed. 

**Internet protocol (IP) address:** The numbers that are translated into a domain name (e.g., progressive.com). The address is a string of four numbers separated by periods (such as 111.22.3.244) used to represent a computer or other device on the Internet. 

**Operating system:** The program responsible for overseeing the basic hardware resources of a computer such as disk drives, memory, keyboard, screen, and CPU. UNIX, DOS, Windows, and Macintosh System 7 are examples of operating systems. 

**Secure server: **A computer and software set up to provide privacy, integrity, and authentication in communications such as a connection on the Internet between a Web browser and a Web server. (See SSL).

**Security protocol:** A specification that describes how computers will talk securely to each other on a computer network.   
**  
Secure Sockets Layer (SSL):** A protocol that delivers server authentication, data encryption, and message integrity. With SSL implemented, Internet communications are transmitted in a secure, encrypted manner. The information you send is safe, so a third party cannot read or access the information while in transit. 

**Session ID:** The code used to keep track of a person (using a browser) as they interact with a server. Since the server may interact with many people simultaneously, a session ID is needed to keep track of each person individually.   
**  
Site certificate:** Same as a digital certificate, but used on the server rather than at the browser. 

**128 bit encryption:** A way of making data unreadable to everyone except the receiver. An increasingly common way of sending credit card numbers and data over the Internet when conducting commercial transactions; used by SSL.

  |
